Share the Ecstacy!
24 Hour Party People is a comedy, drama, music film
directed by Michael Winterbottom.
Manchester, 1976.
Tony Wilson is an ambitious but frustrated local TV news
reporter looking for a way to make his mark.
After witnessing a life-changing concert by a band known as the Sex Pistols, he persuades his station to televise
one of their performances, and soon Manchester's punk groups are clamoring for him to manage them.
Riding the wave of a musical revolution, Wilson and his friends create
the legendary Factory Records label and The Hacienda club.
Tony Wilson, played by Steve Coogan.
Alan, played by Lennie James.
Rob, played by Paddy Considine.
Lindsay, played by Shirley Henderson.
Martin, played by Andy Serkis.
Bernard, played by John Simm.
24 Hour Party People is a 2002 British biographical comedy drama film about Manchester's
popular music community from 1976 to 1992, and specifically about Factory Records.
It was written by Frank Cottrell Boyce and directed by Michael Winterbottom.
The film was entered into the 2002 Cannes Film Festival to positive reviews.
It begins with the punk rock era of the late 1970s and moves through the 1980s into the rave
and DJ culture and the "Madchester" scene of the late 1980s and early 1990s.
The main character is Tony Wilson (played by Steve Coogan), a news
reporter for Granada Television and the head of Factory Records.
The narrative largely follows his career, while also covering the careers of the major Factory artists,
especially Joy Division and New Order, A Certain Ratio, the Durutti Column and Happy Mondays.
The film is a dramatisation based on a combination of real events, rumours, urban
legends and the imaginings of the scriptwriter, as the film makes clear.
In one scene, one-time Buzzcocks member Howard Devoto (played by Martin Hancock) is shown having sex with Wilson's first wife in the toilets
of a club; the real Devoto, an extra in the scene, turns to the camera and says, "I definitely don't remember this happening".
The fourth wall is frequently broken, with Wilson (who also acts as the narrator) frequently commenting on events directly
to camera as they occur, at one point declaring that he is "being postmodern, before it's fashionable".
The actors are often intercut with real contemporary concert footage, including the
Sex Pistols' June and July 1976 gig at the Lesser Free Trade Hall.
The film explores themes of northern england, based on
novel or book, 1970s, nightclub, clubbing.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.